so in cycle 13 what happens is this rob2
instruction finally writes its result
this result is 12. we mark now this
instruction as done
and the value of 12 will be broadcast
under the name of rob2 so now these
instructions here are waiting
for their
inputs and this one here matches that
you know i'm waiting for rob2 value so
it captures it
here this is the first operand that
we're waiting for
the second operand was already there
since a while ago so this instruction
which is the rob4 instruction
is no longer waiting for anything it can
actually dispatch in this cycle 13 and
in cycle 14 the fourth instruction
begins executing
none of the other instructions are
waiting for rob2
so this concludes what happens when we
broadcast the value in cycle 13 for the
rob2 instruction what now happens is
again in cycle 14 we begin
executing this multiplication
and
because it has begun executing in this
cycle this reservation station is
already free it was freed when we
dispatched in the previous cycle so i'm
going to note that this multiplication
of 12 and 13 which gives us 36 is going
to end up in row 4 eventually here but
it's not going to be done until
10 cycles from cycle 14 so it's going to
be in cycle 24 that we try to write the
result
these two instructions still are waiting
for rob4 and rob 5 instructions and this
happens beyond cycle 14. so in cycles 15
16 etc nothing really happens in fact
nothing will happen until we have
another broadcast of a result
and the results we will broadcast
eventually are going to be in 42 and 24
24 comes first so let's see what happens
in cycle 24. in cycle 24 the fourth
instruction will broadcast the result
this is the the multiplication here so
what's going to happen is
the value of 36 is going to be broadcast
under the name of rob4 this instruction
is waiting for rob4 so it's going to
capture the value of 36 and mark that we
are no longer waiting for this operand
this instruction actually
now doesn't wait for anything anymore so
in cycle 25 the subtract is going to
start executing meanwhile our rob4
instruction gets marked as done
basically this value of 36 that was
broadcast also gets kind of deposited
here and marked as done in the rob and
this kind of concludes what happens with
this multiplication instruction
as far as pre-commit stuff is concerned
it cannot commit yet again because it we
need all of these to commit before it
can commit so it's still going to be at
least cycle 43 before we consider
committing anything in the cycle 24
however the rob 5 instruction will be
dispatched and it will begin again
executing in cycle 25 so let's just move
to cycle 25.